Saif Ahmad Kayani

+923329966275 | saifahmedkayani@gmail.com | GitHub: https://github.com/saif-ahmad-k

Professional Summary

Throughout my career, I've worked as an Integration Engineer, developer, SQA and Support Engineer. This is because I love learning new tools & technologies and providing solutions using modern technology. I have been part of Digital Financial Services, Transmission & ERP teams and worked on different stages in SDLC. I enjoy working on databases and performing analysis. I also have exposure in interfacing systems to another and writing automated scripts be it in bash/python/c#.

Experience

Implementation and Support Consultant | SQA, Digitata Networks (Remote) Responsibilities:

10/2021 - current

- Implement and install solutions on the customer's test and production environments.
- Working together with a Quality Assurance (QA) team to assess product problems and brainstorm solutions.
- Act positively and respond promptly to the customer's requests/tickets.
- Troubleshoot and diagnose customer reported issues on the different levels of solutions (i.e. Database, Application, Network, Communication, and Integration Interfaces Levels).
- Writing and reviewing testing plans and creating test plan automation procedures
- Creating automation scripts (bash/python).
- Working on the product design phase and gathering data.
- Applying technical skills related to the product being tested (knowledge of programming languages to software OA)

Associate IT Alternate Delivery Channels, Mobilink Microfinance Bank, Islamabad Responsibilities:

09/2018 - 10/2021

- Provide support for all applications on all Production Systems.
 - Deployments and integration on all Production Systems.
 - Performing User Acceptance Testing & System Integration Testing of all patches and releases.
 - Management of Servers Configuration of new ADC terminals & deployment of new products
 - Database Scripting (Oracle, SQL)
 - Responsible for training internal unit staff to ensure that primary and backup resources are available.
 - Monitor & update of Channel operations. Coordinate with I.T/Vendor/Business for a smooth operation.

Junior Developer, Extend.se, Islamabad

02/2018 - 09/2018

Responsibilities:

- .NET Development, Database Development & Application Deployments
- XML Mapping and Parsing

Junior Developer, NETTECH Pvt Ltd, Islamabad

10/2017 - 01/2018

Responsibilities:

Desktop Applications Development

Additional Skills

- QA Testing tools Selenium, JMeter
- Database Operations MS SQL, DynamoDB, Oracle, MySql, Elastic Search, Postgres
- Scripting PowerShell, CMD, Linux RHEL
- Programming C#, VB, SQL, HTML, Python
- Software Versioning Control TFS, JIRA, Git, Fork
- Business Intelligence PowerBI, Microsoft Excel, Anaconda Python
- Server Management Synchronization, Archiving, Storage Management
- Documentation User Manuals, Test Cases, UATs, SITs.
- Other Tools VS, PyCharm, AWS Management Console, ComponentOne, Altova Mapforce

Education